SOMESH KHADE

Full Stack Developer

√ 7387791658 @ khadesomesh3@gmail.com ② github.io/avtararya

Mumbai, IN

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

2023 - Present

Mediscus Healthcare pvt Itd

Mumabi, In

- Successfully converted whole project from Hapi Fhir Server 2 to 4.1.0
- Designed and implemented APIs using HAPI FHIR to facilitate seamless interoperability between different healthcare systems.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure FHIR standards compliance and adherence to industry best practices.
- Successfully upgraded legacy systems from HAPI FHIR Server 2 to version 4.1.0, enhancing compatibility and performance.
- Utilized HAPI FHIR to integrate standardized health data exchange capabilities into the platform, resulting in improved data accuracy and sharing.
- Implemented FHIR-based authorization and authentication mechanisms to ensure data security and privacy.
- · Worked on technologies such as ReactJS, Python, Django and Postgres

Software Engineer

2022 - 2023

Viser Solutions

Mumabi,In

- Developed full-stack web application. Completed all phases of planning, developing, and debugging web applications and software accurately.
 Managed time-sensitive updates, such as changing content and upgrading databases.
- Ensure that applications are secure and that they can interact with multiple APIs and databases
- Worked on technologies such as ReactJS, NextJS, Python, Django and Postgres

Software Developer

2021 - 2022

One UPI

Mumabi,In

- Built a Fullstack web application focusing on property Listing and booking with Paypal Payment Integration, Google maps api and Google and Facebook authentication.
- Implemented enhancements that improved web functionality and responsiveness.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, such as changing content and upgrading databases.
- Performed root cause analysis for more than 10 issues to identify bugs and rolled out fixes to production within 24 hours
- Worked on technologies such as NextJS, Python, Django and MongoDB

Junior Software Engineer

2020 - 2021

RHA Technologies

Mumabi,In

- Delivered responsive, cross-browser compatible and accessibility compliant websites.
- Created, maintained, and enforced front-end code and documentation standards.
- Implemented enhancements that improved web functionality and responsiveness.
- Worked on technologies such as HTML, CSS, and Javascript

Mahatma Gandhi Mission's College of Engineering and

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2016 - 2020

Technology

Mumbai, MH

Diploma In Information Technology

2013 - 2016

Government Polytechnic College

Jalna, MH

4.1.0

performance.

ACHIEVEMENTS

As a Software Engineer at Mediscus Healthcare Pvt Ltd, I orchestrated the successful migration of the entire project from HAPI FHIR Server 2 to the advanced version 4.1.0. This achievement showcased my technical proficiency, project management skills, and dedication to maintaining high standards of compatibility and

Seamless Transition to HAPI FHIR

Responsive Web Development

As a Junior Software Engineer at RHA Technologies, I excelled in delivering responsive, cross-browser compatible, and accessibility-compliant websites. My attention to detail and commitment to user experience contributed to enhancing the digital presence of the organization.

SKILLS

Operating Systems

Unix · Ventura · Linux · Windows

Tools

React JS · TypeScript · Postgres ·

MongoDB · Next JS · Python Django ·

Node JS. · Python Flask · Nest JS · AWS ·

Figma ..TypeORM . Angular

STRENGTHS

★ Strong Problem-Solving Skills

Demonstrated ability to analyze complex issues, identify root causes, and develop effective solutions, leading to improved project outcomes and streamlined processes.

★ Innovative Thinking

Creative problem solver who brings fresh perspectives to challenges, devising innovative solutions that drive efficiency and effectiveness.